<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networks on GGVY</title>
    <link>/tags/networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networks on GGVY</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 George G. Vega Yon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Read viz attributes from GEXF files</title>
      <link>/post/read-viz-attributes-from-gexf-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/read-viz-attributes-from-gexf-files/</guid>
      <description>So one of the new features that I’ve working on is processing viz attributes. In the CRAN version of rgexf, the function read.gexf only reads in non-visual attributes and the graph structure itself, which is no longer true as of today (at least for the static viz attributes, all the other dynamic features supported by GEXF will come in the future).
We start by loading the R packages and reading the “lesmiserables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reboot of rgexf</title>
      <link>/post/reboot-of-rgexf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reboot-of-rgexf/</guid>
      <description>The rgexf R package has been around a couple of years now, but without much going on on CRAN (my bad!). In this post I’ll show how to use the new version (on development and soon the be shipped to CRAN) together with the netdiffuseR R package to visualize a random diffusion process.
First, we load all the packages that we will be using
# Loading the relevant packages library(igraph, quietly = TRUE) library(rgexf, quietly = TRUE) library(netdiffuseR, quietly = TRUE) Next, we simulate a random diffusion network, in this case, a small-world network with 200 nodes spanning 20 time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netdiffuseR: Analysis of Diffusion and Contagion Processes on Networks</title>
      <link>/project/netdiffuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/netdiffuser/</guid>
      <description>Empirical statistical analysis, visualization and simulation of diffusion and contagion processes on networks. The package implements algorithms for calculating network diffusion statistics such as transmission rate, hazard rates, exposure models, network threshold levels, infectiousness (contagion), and susceptibility. The package is inspired by work published in Valente, et al., (2015) DOI:10.1016/j.socscimed.2015.10.001; Valente (1995) ISBN:9781881303213, Myers (2000) DOI:10.1086&amp;frasl;303110, Iyengar and others (2011) DOI:10.1287/mksc.1100.0566, Burt (1987) DOI:10.1086&amp;frasl;228667; among others.
More details here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>